

Gadigal Land of the Eora Nation Sydney, New South Wales

0434 235 289 hello@mariahlattas.com

www.mariahlattas.com @mariahlattas

www.linkedin.com/in/mariahlattas

Profile

A 24-year-old journalist, podcaster, and writer working on Gadigal Land, in Sydney, New South Wales. Currently working as a *Journalist and Newsletter Editor* for pioneering social-first news organisation *The Daily Aus*. My skills sit at the intersection of technology, young people, explainer journalism, and democracy.

I have experience working for youth-focused news media companies including *The Daily Aus*, *SIMPLIFIED*, *Radio Adelaide*, *postup*, and global brands *Ryderwear* and *Apple*. I am passionate about telling important stories, giving a voice to those who do not have the ability to do so and to hold those who do have a voice accountable.

Experience

Journalist and Newsletter Editor at The Daily Aus — 2021-Present

The Daily Aus is an Australian social-first news organisation, delivering accessible and digestible news to over 340,000 young Australians on Instagram. I joined as the company's first full-time employee, and during my time:

- I helped grow the core <u>@TheDailyAus</u> Instagram account from approximately 80,000 followers to over 340,000;
- Launched the flagship daily <u>newsletter</u> and grew to several thousand daily readers;
- I am a main script writer and occasional host for the flagship <u>The Daily Aus</u>
 <u>Podcast</u>, which consistently ranks in the top 10 news podcasts in Australia
- And reported original stories on emerging issues at the intersection of technology and democracy.

Journalist and Researcher at SIMPLIFIED — 2020-2021

<u>SIMPLIFIED</u> is a media organisation finding a new way to engage with politics. Its mission is "politics, simplified" and empowers a new generation of voices through graphic and video explainers on their Instagram <u>@NowSimplifed</u>— reaching over 1 million people each week. I researched and wrote explainers and deep dives on contemporary complex political issues.

Content Writer and Executive Producer & Host, *What The Flex?* at Ryderwear and PUSHH — 2020-2021

Ryderwear is an Adelaide based activewear company. My role included writing content for the Ryderwear blog, website, and EDMs. I was the Executive Producer and Host of the What The Flex? YouTube and audio podcast. Additionally, I took care of the News Feed for the PUSHH Fitness app, keeping users up to date in the latest health and fitness news.

Co-host, *The Milkbar* at postup — 2019-2020

postup was an independent, youth-centric media company based in Adelaide focusing on culture and sport. *The Milkbar* was a podcast about culture co-hosted with Benito Carbone. Covering culture and current affairs, produced weekly.

Journalist and Host. Pink Rabbit at Radio Adelaide — 2018-2020

A 21st century feminist podcast broadcast weekly on Radio Adelaide 101.5FM and Joy 94.9 FM in Melbourne. Serving as both journalist and host with Milly Shultz-Boylen, Soph Landau and Phoebe Montgomery.

Journalist, The Wire at Radio Adelaide - 2018

Covered news and current affairs, writing, interviewing, producing and voicing multiple packages that were syndicated to five radio stations nationally: 2SER in Sydney; 4EB in Brisbane; CAAMA RADIO Alice Springs; RTR-FM in Perth; and JOY 94.9 in Melbourne.

Placement at Channel 7 Adelaide - 2018

University placement working mainly with political journalist, Mike Smithson, working on stories primarily related to politics.

Placement at Channel 10 Adelaide - 2018

University placement shadowing multiple journalists and working with the newsroom.

Operations Specialist at Apple — 2017-2019

Previous role: Product Specialist. Oversees the daily operations and inventory management of South Australia's only Apple Retail Store.

Education

University of Adelaide; Bachelor of Media and Bachelor of Arts, Major in Politics and International Relations — 2016-2019

In 2017, studied at the University of Adelaide's Singapore campus under a *New Colombo Plan Scholarship*. Also, completed a short course at Seisen University, Japan in 2019 and in 2020 completing a politics study tour to Illinois and Iowa Caucus in the United States to cover and observe the *2020 Presidential Election Primary campaigns*. I was lucky enough to even feature current U.S. President Joe Biden on my Instagram story.

Key Skills

Writing, researching, producing and editing packages for radio and podcast.

Strong interviewing skills with the ability to distil and summarise the interviewees words to form a concise story.

Extensive experience in multi-platform digital and social news delivery.

Fast-paced work environments including large multinational and startups.

Expansive world political and cultural awareness and experience, well travelled and highly educated on political frameworks and theories as they apply to the current landscape.

Experience in traditional news media — Channel 7 and Channel 10, in new and online media — postup, SIMPLIFED, and The Daily Aus, and community media — Radio Adelaide.

References

Available upon request